A Guide to the Papers of Edmund Jennings Lee, 1786-1821
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Edmund Jennings Lee, 1786-1821
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9741
This collection contains 27 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased from Charles Hamilton Galleries, Inc., New York, New York, on August 25, 1971.
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains business correspondence and legal documents of Lee including: summonses, legal briefs, court records, and statements regarding various cases.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Summons for witnesses re: Henry Lee vs. Thomas Marshall 1786 Apr 7, ADS
- Indenture, Michael and Hannah Madden 1786 Dec 20, ADS
- Summons for Michael Madden 1792 Oct 1, ADS
  Re: Michael Madden vs. Estate of William Sidebotham
- Receipts 1975 May 25 & 1798 Apr 2, ANS, 2 items
- Joseph Forrest to Edmund Jennings Lee 1798 Jul 16, ALS
- Joseph Forrest to Edmund Jennings Lee 1798 Aug 9, ALS
- Opie Lindsay to Edmund Jennings Lee 1798 Aug 22, ALS
- Edmund Jennings Lee to Court of Appeals 1800 Aug 6, ALS
- Gray (from Havana, Cuba) to "Dear, Sir" 1802 Sep 15, ALS
- Court Record, William Wilson vs. Adam Stuart 1802 Sep 29, ADS copy
- Legal brief, Ferdinand Fairfax vs. Francis Kean 1804 Jun 6, ADS
- Charles G. Paleske to Edmund Jennings Lee 1805 Jan 4, ALS
- Alexander Henderson to Lewis Summers 1806 Jan 30, ALS
- Note signed by R. Moss 1806 Jun 25, ANS
- Deposition re: John Foushee vs. James Laurason 1806 Jun 26, ANS
- Legal brief, John Foushee vs. James Laurason 1806 Jun 26, ADS
- Deposition of Septimus Levering 1806 Jun 27, ADS
  Re: John Foushee vs. James Laurason
- James Waugh vs. Neill Mooney, Abedusgo Adams, and Joseph Riddle 1807 Feb 4, AD frag.
- Prison warrant: John Wise vs. John Curson Seaton 1809 May 12, AD
- Statement of court costs: James Jackson and John Livingston vs. James Eddy 1809, ADS
- Summons: John Hopkins vs. Richard Bland Lee, Edmund Jennings Lee, and Walter Jones, Jr. 1817 Nov 22, ADS
- To Charles Lee 1819 Nov 19, ALS
- Legal brief: Newton Admors vs. Mills, et al 1819 Dec 1, ADS
- Petition: Noblet Herbert to Circuit Court 1821 Oct 29, AD copy
  Re: John Hopkins vs. Richard Bland Lee
- Extract of letter from John Hopkins 1821 Nov 30, AL copy
- Edmund Jennings Lee to Noblet Herbert 1821 Dec 8, ALS